ADAM WILLIAMS

williams_adam@icloud.com linkedin.com/in/williams-adam github.com/awilliams Denver, CO

Profile

Professional software engineer with 13+ years experience. Focused on Go, clean code, quality, simplicity, and mentoring. Experience leading project development and working collaboratively as part of a distributed team.

Technical

Go (golang), Ruby, Javascript Swift, Python, PHP, Java Kubernetes, Docker, Helm

Git, SVN

Puppet, Ansible, AWS, Linux Prometheus, Grafana

Experience

Comcast Engineer Level 4

February 2015 — Present Comcast Cable

- Implement and design MPEG-TS parsing library in **Go** to build application to monitor hundreds of video streams in order to provide metrics using **Go**, **Prometheus**, **Docker**, **and Kubernetes**. Create automated testing framework leading to improved accuracy and development speed.
- Design and build native Go client for Apache Pulsar, collaborating with core project developers. Project was released as open-source by Comcast (github.com/Comcast/pulsar-client-go). Build distributed system for object replication.
- Develop projects as a tech lead. Mentored fellow engineers. Participant of Open Source Fellowship Program and receiver of award for top contributor.
- Build core components used for TCP & UDP custom protocol communications using Go. Follow specification documents to implement protocols.
- Use Kubernetes and HeIm for national deployment across multiple data centers. Develop custom CNI plugin.
- Create custom network monitoring application. Uncover, debug, and resolve obscure longstanding DNS issue causing problems in production environments.

Cabify

October 2013 — February 2015 cabify.com

- Senior Developer
- Implemented new features and modify existing functionality using RoR, Node.js, Go. Introduced Go to the company, which led to replacement of most Node.js services and improved reliability.
- Provisioned and maintained servers using Ansible, Bash scripts, and Go binaries deployed on Linode and AWS in multiple regions for service provided in 4 countries. Monitored systems with InfluxDB and managed CouchDB replication/backups. Built internal development tools.
- Technologies used: Ruby on Rails (4.x) with Ruby 2.x, CouchDB, Elasticsearch, Redis, ZeroMQ, Go, Node.js, Ansible, Linode, Android.

Incuentra Technologies

July 2010 — October 2013 www.incuentra.es

- Lead Developer
- Led project creation from idea to production stage. Design site architecture; programmed front and backends. Leverage Amazon's EC2, S3, RDS, and IAM services. Maintain servers using Chef and Unix tools. Continuous deployment with Capistrano. Write unit and integration tests. Localized version for Mexico.
- Technologies used: Ruby on Rails (2.x and 4.x) with Ruby 1.8.7 and 2.0.0, MySQL, Solr, AWS.

DixiMedia Developer

December 2008 — July 2010 www.lainformacion.com

• Developed the online newspaper frontend using PHP and the Zend framework. Developed the CMS used by journalists with PHP and Ext. JS.

Interests

Presenter at various Go and Ruby user groups

Co-organizer of Madrid Go meetup. Founder of internal Comcast Go club Home automation

Languages

English (native)

Spanish (fluent)

Education

University of Minnesota

Dual Major, B.S. Mathematics and B.A Spanish Studies